<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<learning_data>
    <!-- Mathematics Subject -->
    <subject name="Mathematics">
        <!-- Algebra Unit -->
        <unit name="Algebra">
            <!-- Linear Equations Topic -->
            <topic name="Linear Equations">
                <card title="Introduction to Linear Equations">
                    Linear equations are mathematical expressions that represent straight lines when graphed on a coordinate plane. They are fundamental in algebra and have numerous real-world applications.
                </card>
                <card title="What is a Linear Equation?">
                    A linear equation is an algebraic equation where each term is either a constant or the product of a constant and a single variable. The general form is ax + b = 0, where 'a' and 'b' are constants and 'x' is the variable.
                </card>
                <card title="Standard Form">
                    The standard form of a linear equation is written as ax + by = c, where a, b, and c are constants (integers), and a and b are not both zero. This form is useful for graphing and solving systems of equations.
                </card>
                <card title="Slope-Intercept Form">
                    The slope-intercept form is y = mx + b, where 'm' represents the slope of the line and 'b' represents the y-intercept (where the line crosses the y-axis). This form makes it easy to identify the slope and y-intercept directly.
                </card>
                <card title="Point-Slope Form">
                    The point-slope form is y - y₁ = m(x - x₁), where (x₁, y₁) is a known point on the line and 'm' is the slope. This form is particularly useful when you know a point on the line and its slope.
                </card>
                
                <quiz question="What is the slope-intercept form of a linear equation?" correct="0">
                    <option>y = mx + b</option>
                    <option>ax + by = c</option>
                    <option>y - y₁ = m(x - x₁)</option>
                    <option>x = my + b</option>
                </quiz>
                
                <card title="Finding the Slope">
                    The slope of a line passing through two points (x₁, y₁) and (x₂, y₂) is calculated using the formula: m = (y₂ - y₁) / (x₂ - x₁). The slope represents the rate of change or steepness of the line.
                </card>
                <card title="Y-Intercept">
                    The y-intercept is the point where the line crosses the y-axis. It occurs when x = 0. In the slope-intercept form y = mx + b, the y-intercept is simply the value of 'b'.
                </card>
                <card title="X-Intercept">
                    The x-intercept is the point where the line crosses the x-axis. It occurs when y = 0. To find it, substitute y = 0 into the equation and solve for x.
                </card>
                <card title="Graphing Linear Equations">
                    To graph a linear equation, you can use various methods: plot two points and draw a line through them, use the slope and y-intercept, or find the x and y intercepts and connect them.
                </card>
                <card title="Real-World Applications">
                    Linear equations are used to model relationships in business (profit/loss), science (temperature conversion), economics (supply/demand), and many other fields where there's a constant rate of change.
                </card>
                
                <quiz question="If a line passes through points (2, 3) and (4, 7), what is its slope?" correct="2">
                    <option>1</option>
                    <option>3</option>
                    <option>2</option>
                    <option>4</option>
                </quiz>
            </topic>
            
            <!-- Quadratic Equations Topic -->
            <topic name="Quadratic Equations">
                <card title="Definition of Quadratic Equations">
                    A quadratic equation is a polynomial equation of degree 2, meaning the highest power of the variable is 2. The general form is ax² + bx + c = 0, where a ≠ 0.
                </card>
                <card title="Types of Quadratic Equations">
                    Quadratic equations can be classified as: Complete (has all three terms), Incomplete (missing the linear or constant term), Pure (only has the quadratic and constant terms), or Monic (where a = 1).
                </card>
                <card title="The Discriminant">
                    The discriminant (Δ = b² - 4ac) determines the nature of roots: If Δ > 0, there are two distinct real roots; if Δ = 0, there's one repeated real root; if Δ < 0, there are two complex roots.
                </card>
                <card title="Factoring Method">
                    Some quadratic equations can be solved by factoring the expression into two binomials. For example, x² - 5x + 6 = 0 can be factored as (x - 2)(x - 3) = 0.
                </card>
                <card title="Quadratic Formula">
                    The quadratic formula x = (-b ± √(b² - 4ac)) / 2a can solve any quadratic equation. It's derived by completing the square on the general form.
                </card>
                
                <quiz question="What is the general form of a quadratic equation?" correct="1">
                    <option>ax + b = 0</option>
                    <option>ax² + bx + c = 0</option>
                    <option>ax³ + bx² + cx + d = 0</option>
                    <option>y = mx + b</option>
                </quiz>
                
                <card title="Completing the Square">
                    This method involves manipulating the equation to create a perfect square trinomial. It's useful for solving equations and converting to vertex form.
                </card>
                <card title="Graphing Quadratics">
                    Quadratic equations graph as parabolas. The vertex is at x = -b/2a, and the parabola opens upward if a > 0 or downward if a < 0.
                </card>
                <card title="Vertex Form">
                    The vertex form is y = a(x - h)² + k, where (h, k) is the vertex of the parabola. This form makes it easy to identify the vertex and transformations.
                </card>
                <card title="Applications">
                    Quadratic equations model projectile motion, profit maximization, optimization problems, and any situation involving squared relationships.
                </card>
                <card title="Sum and Product of Roots">
                    For equation ax² + bx + c = 0, the sum of roots is -b/a and the product of roots is c/a. These relationships are known as Vieta's formulas.
                </card>
                
                <quiz question="What does the discriminant tell us about a quadratic equation?" correct="0">
                    <option>The nature of the roots</option>
                    <option>The vertex location</option>
                    <option>The y-intercept</option>
                    <option>The axis of symmetry</option>
                </quiz>
            </topic>
        </unit>
        
        <!-- Geometry Unit -->
        <unit name="Geometry">
            <topic name="Triangles">
                <card title="Types of Triangles">
                    Triangles can be classified by sides (equilateral, isosceles, scalene) or by angles (acute, right, obtuse). Each type has unique properties and applications.
                </card>
                <card title="Triangle Inequality">
                    The triangle inequality states that the sum of the lengths of any two sides of a triangle must be greater than the length of the third side.
                </card>
                <card title="Pythagorean Theorem">
                    In a right triangle, the square of the hypotenuse equals the sum of squares of the other two sides: a² + b² = c².
                </card>
                <card title="Area Formulas">
                    The area of a triangle can be calculated using: ½ × base × height, Heron's formula, or ½ab sin(C) where a and b are sides and C is the included angle.
                </card>
                <card title="Congruence and Similarity">
                    Triangles are congruent if they have the same size and shape. They're similar if they have the same shape but different sizes, with proportional corresponding sides.
                </card>
                
                <quiz question="What is the Pythagorean theorem?" correct="2">
                    <option>a + b = c</option>
                    <option>a² + b = c²</option>
                    <option>a² + b² = c²</option>
                    <option>a × b = c</option>
                </quiz>
            </topic>
        </unit>
    </subject>
    
    <!-- Physics Subject -->
    <subject name="Physics">
        <unit name="Mechanics">
            <topic name="Motion">
                <card title="Types of Motion">
                    Motion can be classified as linear (straight line), rotational (around an axis), oscillatory (back and forth), or random (unpredictable path). Each type has specific characteristics and equations.
                </card>
                <card title="Distance vs Displacement">
                    Distance is the total length of path traveled (scalar quantity), while displacement is the straight-line distance from start to finish point (vector quantity with direction).
                </card>
                <card title="Speed vs Velocity">
                    Speed is the rate of change of distance with time (scalar), while velocity is the rate of change of displacement with time (vector with direction).
                </card>
                <card title="Acceleration">
                    Acceleration is the rate of change of velocity with respect to time. It's measured in m/s² and can be positive (speeding up) or negative (slowing down).
                </card>
                <card title="Equations of Motion">
                    The three kinematic equations relate initial velocity (u), final velocity (v), acceleration (a), time (t), and displacement (s): v = u + at, s = ut + ½at², v² = u² + 2as.
                </card>
                
                <quiz question="What is the difference between speed and velocity?" correct="1">
                    <option>No difference</option>
                    <option>Velocity includes direction</option>
                    <option>Speed is always faster</option>
                    <option>Velocity is measured in different units</option>
                </quiz>
                
                <card title="Uniform Motion">
                    Uniform motion occurs when an object travels equal distances in equal intervals of time, meaning constant velocity and zero acceleration.
                </card>
                <card title="Non-Uniform Motion">
                    Non-uniform motion involves changing velocity over time, resulting in non-zero acceleration. Most real-world motion is non-uniform.
                </card>
                <card title="Relative Motion">
                    Motion is relative to the observer's frame of reference. An object can appear stationary to one observer but moving to another.
                </card>
                <card title="Graphical Representation">
                    Motion can be represented using position-time, velocity-time, and acceleration-time graphs. The slope and area under curves provide important information.
                </card>
                <card title="Free Fall">
                    Free fall is motion under gravity alone, with acceleration g = 9.8 m/s² downward (neglecting air resistance). All objects fall at the same rate regardless of mass.
                </card>
                
                <quiz question="What is the acceleration due to gravity on Earth?" correct="1">
                    <option>9.8 m/s</option>
                    <option>9.8 m/s²</option>
                    <option>98 m/s²</option>
                    <option>0.98 m/s²</option>
                </quiz>
            </topic>
            
            <topic name="Forces">
                <card title="Newton's First Law">
                    An object at rest stays at rest, and an object in motion stays in motion at constant velocity, unless acted upon by an unbalanced force. This is the law of inertia.
                </card>
                <card title="Newton's Second Law">
                    The acceleration of an object is directly proportional to the net force acting on it and inversely proportional to its mass: F = ma.
                </card>
                <card title="Newton's Third Law">
                    For every action, there is an equal and opposite reaction. Forces always occur in pairs between interacting objects.
                </card>
                <card title="Types of Forces">
                    Forces can be contact forces (friction, normal, tension) or non-contact forces (gravitational, electric, magnetic). Each has specific characteristics and applications.
                </card>
                <card title="Force Diagrams">
                    Free body diagrams show all forces acting on an object. They help analyze motion and solve problems involving multiple forces.
                </card>
                
                <quiz question="What does Newton's second law state?" correct="0">
                    <option>F = ma</option>
                    <option>F = mv</option>
                    <option>F = m/a</option>
                    <option>F = ma²</option>
                </quiz>
            </topic>
        </unit>
        
        <unit name="Thermodynamics">
            <topic name="Heat and Temperature">
                <card title="Difference Between Heat and Temperature">
                    Temperature is a measure of average kinetic energy of particles, while heat is the transfer of thermal energy between objects at different temperatures.
                </card>
                <card title="Temperature Scales">
                    Common temperature scales include Celsius (°C), Fahrenheit (°F), and Kelvin (K). Kelvin is the absolute temperature scale starting from absolute zero.
                </card>
                <card title="Heat Transfer Methods">
                    Heat transfers through conduction (direct contact), convection (fluid movement), and radiation (electromagnetic waves). Each method has different characteristics.
                </card>
                <card title="Specific Heat Capacity">
                    The amount of heat energy required to raise the temperature of 1 kg of a substance by 1°C. Different materials have different specific heat capacities.
                </card>
                <card title="Thermal Expansion">
                    Most materials expand when heated and contract when cooled. This property has important applications in engineering and construction.
                </card>
                
                <quiz question="What is the SI unit of temperature?" correct="2">
                    <option>Celsius</option>
                    <option>Fahrenheit</option>
                    <option>Kelvin</option>
                    <option>Joule</option>
                </quiz>
            </topic>
        </unit>
    </subject>
    
    <!-- Chemistry Subject -->
    <subject name="Chemistry">
        <unit name="Atomic Structure">
            <topic name="Atoms and Elements">
                <card title="What is an Atom?">
                    An atom is the smallest unit of an element that retains the chemical properties of that element. It consists of protons, neutrons, and electrons.
                </card>
                <card title="Atomic Structure">
                    Atoms have a nucleus containing protons and neutrons, surrounded by electrons in shells or energy levels. The nucleus is extremely small but contains most of the atom's mass.
                </card>
                <card title="Atomic Number">
                    The atomic number equals the number of protons in an atom's nucleus. It defines the element and determines its position in the periodic table.
                </card>
                <card title="Mass Number">
                    The mass number is the sum of protons and neutrons in an atom's nucleus. Isotopes of an element have the same atomic number but different mass numbers.
                </card>
                <card title="Electronic Configuration">
                    Electrons occupy specific energy levels or shells around the nucleus. The arrangement of electrons determines the chemical properties of elements.
                </card>
                
                <quiz question="What determines the atomic number of an element?" correct="1">
                    <option>Number of neutrons</option>
                    <option>Number of protons</option>
                    <option>Number of electrons</option>
                    <option>Total mass</option>
                </quiz>
            </topic>
        </unit>
    </subject>
    
    <!-- Biology Subject -->
    <subject name="Biology">
        <unit name="Cell Biology">
            <topic name="Cell Structure">
                <card title="What is a Cell?">
                    A cell is the basic structural and functional unit of all living organisms. All life forms are composed of one or more cells.
                </card>
                <card title="Types of Cells">
                    There are two main types: prokaryotic cells (no nucleus, like bacteria) and eukaryotic cells (with nucleus, like plant and animal cells).
                </card>
                <card title="Cell Membrane">
                    The cell membrane is a selectively permeable barrier that controls what enters and exits the cell. It's made of a phospholipid bilayer with embedded proteins.
                </card>
                <card title="Nucleus">
                    The nucleus is the control center of eukaryotic cells, containing DNA and controlling cellular activities like growth, reproduction, and metabolism.
                </card>
                <card title="Organelles">
                    Organelles are specialized structures within cells that perform specific functions, such as mitochondria (energy production) and ribosomes (protein synthesis).
                </card>
                
                <quiz question="What is the main difference between prokaryotic and eukaryotic cells?" correct="0">
                    <option>Presence of nucleus</option>
                    <option>Cell size</option>
                    <option>Cell membrane</option>
                    <option>DNA content</option>
                </quiz>
            </topic>
        </unit>
    </subject>
</learning_data>
