<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<courses>
    <!-- Mathematics Subject -->
    <subject name="Mathematics" id="math">
        <unit name="Algebra" id="algebra">
            <topic name="Linear Equations" id="linear_equations">
                <card type="info">
                    <title>Introduction to Linear Equations</title>
                    <content>A linear equation is a mathematical equation that describes a straight line when graphed. It has the general form y = mx + b, where m is the slope and b is the y-intercept.</content>
                </card>
                <card type="info">
                    <title>Types of Linear Equations</title>
                    <content>There are three main forms: Standard Form (Ax + By = C), Slope-intercept Form (y = mx + b), and Point-slope Form (y - y₁ = m(x - x₁)).</content>
                </card>
                <card type="info">
                    <title>Solving Linear Equations</title>
                    <content>To solve a linear equation, isolate the variable by performing inverse operations on both sides of the equation. Always maintain equality by doing the same operation to both sides.</content>
                </card>
                <card type="info">
                    <title>Graphing Linear Equations</title>
                    <content>Linear equations graph as straight lines. The slope determines steepness and direction, while the y-intercept shows where the line crosses the y-axis.</content>
                </card>
                <card type="info">
                    <title>Applications</title>
                    <content>Linear equations are used in real-world scenarios like calculating costs, distance-time relationships, and business profit models.</content>
                </card>
            </topic>
            
            <topic name="Quadratic Equations" id="quadratic_equations">
                <card type="info">
                    <title>What are Quadratic Equations?</title>
                    <content>A quadratic equation is a polynomial equation of degree 2, with the standard form ax² + bx + c = 0, where a ≠ 0.</content>
                </card>
                <card type="info">
                    <title>The Quadratic Formula</title>
                    <content>The quadratic formula x = (-b ± √(b² - 4ac)) / 2a can solve any quadratic equation. The discriminant (b² - 4ac) determines the nature of roots.</content>
                </card>
                <card type="info">
                    <title>Factoring Method</title>
                    <content>Many quadratic equations can be solved by factoring into two binomials. Find two numbers that multiply to 'ac' and add to 'b'.</content>
                </card>
                <card type="info">
                    <title>Completing the Square</title>
                    <content>This method involves creating a perfect square trinomial by adding and subtracting the same value to complete the square.</content>
                </card>
                <card type="info">
                    <title>Graphing Parabolas</title>
                    <content>Quadratic equations graph as parabolas. The vertex form y = a(x - h)² + k shows the vertex at (h, k) and whether the parabola opens up or down.</content>
                </card>
            </topic>
        </unit>
        
        <unit name="Geometry" id="geometry">
            <topic name="Triangles" id="triangles">
                <card type="info">
                    <title>Types of Triangles</title>
                    <content>Triangles can be classified by sides: Equilateral (all sides equal), Isosceles (two sides equal), and Scalene (all sides different).</content>
                </card>
                <card type="info">
                    <title>Triangle Angles</title>
                    <content>The sum of interior angles in any triangle is always 180°. Triangles can also be classified by angles: Acute, Right, and Obtuse.</content>
                </card>
                <card type="info">
                    <title>Pythagorean Theorem</title>
                    <content>In a right triangle, a² + b² = c², where c is the hypotenuse and a, b are the other two sides. This fundamental theorem has countless applications.</content>
                </card>
                <card type="info">
                    <title>Triangle Congruence</title>
                    <content>Triangles are congruent if they have the same shape and size. Congruence can be proven using SSS, SAS, ASA, AAS, or HL postulates.</content>
                </card>
                <card type="info">
                    <title>Triangle Similarity</title>
                    <content>Similar triangles have the same shape but different sizes. Their corresponding angles are equal and corresponding sides are proportional.</content>
                </card>
            </topic>
        </unit>
    </subject>
    
    <!-- Physics Subject -->
    <subject name="Physics" id="physics">
        <unit name="Mechanics" id="mechanics">
            <topic name="Motion" id="motion">
                <card type="info">
                    <title>Types of Motion</title>
                    <content>Motion can be linear (straight line), rotational (around an axis), oscillatory (back and forth), or random (unpredictable path).</content>
                </card>
                <card type="info">
                    <title>Distance vs Displacement</title>
                    <content>Distance is the total path traveled (scalar), while displacement is the straight-line distance from start to end point (vector).</content>
                </card>
                <card type="info">
                    <title>Speed vs Velocity</title>
                    <content>Speed is distance traveled per unit time (scalar), while velocity is displacement per unit time (vector) and includes direction.</content>
                </card>
                <card type="info">
                    <title>Acceleration</title>
                    <content>Acceleration is the rate of change of velocity. It can be positive (speeding up), negative (slowing down), or zero (constant velocity).</content>
                </card>
                <card type="info">
                    <title>Equations of Motion</title>
                    <content>The three kinematic equations relate displacement, velocity, acceleration, and time: v = u + at, s = ut + ½at², and v² = u² + 2as.</content>
                </card>
            </topic>
            
            <topic name="Forces" id="forces">
                <card type="info">
                    <title>Newton's First Law</title>
                    <content>An object at rest stays at rest, and an object in motion stays in motion at constant velocity, unless acted upon by an unbalanced force.</content>
                </card>
                <card type="info">
                    <title>Newton's Second Law</title>
                    <content>The acceleration of an object is directly proportional to the net force acting on it and inversely proportional to its mass: F = ma.</content>
                </card>
                <card type="info">
                    <title>Newton's Third Law</title>
                    <content>For every action, there is an equal and opposite reaction. Forces always occur in pairs acting on different objects.</content>
                </card>
                <card type="info">
                    <title>Types of Forces</title>
                    <content>Common forces include gravitational, normal, friction, tension, applied, and elastic forces. Each has unique characteristics and applications.</content>
                </card>
                <card type="info">
                    <title>Free Body Diagrams</title>
                    <content>Free body diagrams show all forces acting on an object. They help analyze motion and solve force problems systematically.</content>
                </card>
            </topic>
        </unit>
    </subject>
    
    <!-- Chemistry Subject -->
    <subject name="Chemistry" id="chemistry">
        <unit name="Atomic Structure" id="atomic_structure">
            <topic name="Atoms" id="atoms">
                <card type="info">
                    <title>Structure of an Atom</title>
                    <content>An atom consists of a nucleus (containing protons and neutrons) surrounded by electrons in energy levels or shells.</content>
                </card>
                <card type="info">
                    <title>Subatomic Particles</title>
                    <content>Protons have positive charge, electrons have negative charge, and neutrons are neutral. Protons and neutrons have nearly equal mass, much greater than electrons.</content>
                </card>
                <card type="info">
                    <title>Atomic Number and Mass</title>
                    <content>Atomic number equals the number of protons and defines the element. Atomic mass is the average mass of all isotopes of an element.</content>
                </card>
                <card type="info">
                    <title>Electron Configuration</title>
                    <content>Electrons occupy specific energy levels and subshells (s, p, d, f) following the aufbau principle, Pauli exclusion principle, and Hund's rule.</content>
                </card>
                <card type="info">
                    <title>Isotopes</title>
                    <content>Isotopes are atoms of the same element with different numbers of neutrons. They have identical chemical properties but different physical properties.</content>
                </card>
            </topic>
        </unit>
    </subject>
    
    <!-- Biology Subject -->
    <subject name="Biology" id="biology">
        <unit name="Cell Biology" id="cell_biology">
            <topic name="Cell Structure" id="cell_structure">
                <card type="info">
                    <title>Cell Theory</title>
                    <content>All living things are made of cells, the cell is the basic unit of life, and all cells come from pre-existing cells.</content>
                </card>
                <card type="info">
                    <title>Prokaryotic vs Eukaryotic</title>
                    <content>Prokaryotic cells lack a membrane-bound nucleus (bacteria), while eukaryotic cells have a nucleus and organelles (plants, animals, fungi).</content>
                </card>
                <card type="info">
                    <title>Cell Membrane</title>
                    <content>The cell membrane is a phospholipid bilayer that controls what enters and exits the cell through selective permeability.</content>
                </card>
                <card type="info">
                    <title>Organelles</title>
                    <content>Key organelles include nucleus (control center), mitochondria (powerhouse), endoplasmic reticulum (transport), and Golgi apparatus (packaging).</content>
                </card>
                <card type="info">
                    <title>Cell Transport</title>
                    <content>Materials move across membranes by passive transport (diffusion, osmosis) or active transport (requiring energy to move against gradients).</content>
                </card>
            </topic>
        </unit>
    </subject>
    
    <!-- English Subject -->
    <subject name="English" id="english">
        <unit name="Grammar" id="grammar">
            <topic name="Parts of Speech" id="parts_of_speech">
                <card type="info">
                    <title>Nouns</title>
                    <content>Nouns are words that name persons, places, things, or ideas. They can be common or proper, concrete or abstract, countable or uncountable.</content>
                </card>
                <card type="info">
                    <title>Pronouns</title>
                    <content>Pronouns replace nouns to avoid repetition. Types include personal, possessive, reflexive, demonstrative, interrogative, and relative pronouns.</content>
                </card>
                <card type="info">
                    <title>Verbs</title>
                    <content>Verbs express actions, states, or occurrences. They can be main verbs, auxiliary verbs, or modal verbs, and change form for tense, mood, and voice.</content>
                </card>
                <card type="info">
                    <title>Adjectives</title>
                    <content>Adjectives describe or modify nouns and pronouns. They can show quality, size, age, color, origin, material, or purpose.</content>
                </card>
                <card type="info">
                    <title>Adverbs</title>
                    <content>Adverbs modify verbs, adjectives, or other adverbs. They often answer how, when, where, or to what extent something happens.</content>
                </card>
            </topic>
        </unit>
    </subject>
    
    <!-- History Subject -->
    <subject name="History" id="history">
        <unit name="Ancient Civilizations" id="ancient_civilizations">
            <topic name="Egyptian Civilization" id="egyptian_civilization">
                <card type="info">
                    <title>Geography and the Nile</title>
                    <content>Ancient Egypt developed along the Nile River, which provided water, fertile soil, and transportation. The predictable flooding cycle enabled agriculture.</content>
                </card>
                <card type="info">
                    <title>Pharaohs and Government</title>
                    <content>Egypt was ruled by pharaohs who were considered divine. The government was highly centralized with a complex bureaucracy of officials and scribes.</content>
                </card>
                <card type="info">
                    <title>Pyramids and Architecture</title>
                    <content>Egyptians built magnificent pyramids as tombs for pharaohs. These structures demonstrate advanced engineering and mathematical knowledge.</content>
                </card>
                <card type="info">
                    <title>Religion and Afterlife</title>
                    <content>Egyptians believed in many gods and goddesses and had elaborate beliefs about the afterlife, leading to mummification and tomb construction.</content>
                </card>
                <card type="info">
                    <title>Hieroglyphics</title>
                    <content>Egyptian writing system using pictures and symbols. The Rosetta Stone was key to deciphering hieroglyphics in modern times.</content>
                </card>
            </topic>
        </unit>
    </subject>
</courses>
